# Yan Yao Chan

(515) 520-5659 | chanyanyao@hotmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/yanyaochan

# Summary

Trilingual, Electrical Engineering graduate with experience in the military. Proven to have strong communication skills along with the ability to articulate in a clear and concise manner to diverse groups of individuals. Possesses critical thinking skills and experience holding leadership roles in the professional setting.

#### Education

Bachelor of Science in Electrical Engineering Iowa State University - Ames, IA

December 2015

# **Key Skills & Qualifications**

- Microelectronics
- Integrated Circuits
- Nanoelectronics

- Interpersonal skills
- Security Clearance
- Written communication
- Software: MATLAB, Java
- Foreign Language: Mandarin Chinese

# Experience

Human Resources Specialist

December 2015 - Present

### United States Army - Tacoma, WA

- Review and submit employees' pay inquiries and leave processing to Department of Defense (DoD) accounting agency with minimal errors in accordance with DoD guidance and regulatory requirements.
- Train and supervise team members to prioritize assignment duties and workload in stressful conditions in order to meet deadlines.
- Developed a plan of action when servicemembers were selected for DoD financial audits and collected the required documentation in a timely manner to ensure individuals' pay and entitlements were not affected.
- Coordinated fire and troop movements as a team leader in remote environments and communicated with team members effectively to achieve tactical proficiency and combat effectiveness.

#### Sales Assistant

August 2015 - December 2015

#### Iowa State University Bookstore - Ames, IA

- Accurately received orders, processed payments at point of sale, and responded promptly to consumers' concerns.
- Performed inventory and stock replenishing, ensuring every asset, surplus, and customer's order is properly accounted for.
- Provided guidance and product suggestions to incoming students to find the best fit for their needs, ensuring that they have the appropriate materials required for college.

#### Sales Assistant

May 2012 - August 2012

## Switch, Apple Premium Reseller - Malaysia

- Accurately input orders and transactions at point of sale to ensure all sales were accounted for.
- Responded to customer inquiries through in-person, telephone, and email correspondences.
- Provided customer service and resolved issues such as incorrect orders, returns, and general servicing in accordance with store's standard operating procedures.